S.RAJA AYYAPPAN

BE(HONS.) Computer Science 59-A,VOC Street, VGN Nagar, Nolambur, Chennai-600 095.

Mob: 8148161310

OBJECTIVE

To work in a company that can help me in improving my technical knowledge and contribute to the growth of the company.

EDUCATION

College and School Education:

Degree/Course	Name of the Institution	Board/ University	Year of Study	CGPA/ Percentage
BE(Hons.) Computer Science	Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani - Dubai	BITS, Pilani	2006 – 2010	7.43
XII th Standard	Southern Pearl Mat.Hr.Sec.School, Chennai	Tamil Nadu State Board, India	2005 – 2006	93.17%
X th Standard	Southern Pearl Mat.Hr.Sec.School, Chennai	Matriculation	2003 – 2004	91.73%

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, J2EE, C, and Excel VBA
- Frameworks: Spring, Hibernate, Weka and GWT
- <u>Scripting:</u> HTML,CSS(basics),Javascript, and jQuery
- <u>Databases tools:</u> MySql and Oracle
- Operating Systems: Windows and Linux.
- Other Skills: MS Office and MATLAB.

FINANCE SKILLS

- 1. Understand the Principles of Corporate Finance.
- 2. Understand the Three Financial Statements Cash Flow Statement, Income Statement and Balance Sheet and the Basics of Accounting.
- 3. Financial Modeling using Excel. Valuation Methods (DCF, Comparable Companies Analysis, Precedent Transactions Analysis, Option Pricing)
- 4. Understand the Basics of Computational Finance.
- 5. Understand the Capital Markets well and a regular investor in the Stock Market.

Online Courses:

- 1. Valuation Aswath Damodaran ,NYU(on Academic Earth)
- 2. Introduction to Computational Finance and Financial Econometrics –Eric Zivot, University of Washington(on Coursera)

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Academic Thesis and Projects

1. Thesis: Design and Analysis of Cloud Computing Architecture: Predicting User Application Execution Time

Duration: Feb 10 to May 10

Description: Proposed an architecture for Infrastructure as a Service and two approaches – by parsing assembly code and by using neural networks were implemented for predicting CPU execution time for an user application. The results were noted and compared.

Tools Used: Java, MATLAB (for simulating Neural Network)

2. Project: Implementation of Normalization techniques on Classification Algorithms

Duration: Sep 06 to Dec 06

Description: Studied about data mining and its tasks. Understood the need for normalization of datasets and implemented those techniques using Java and studied its impact with reference to a classification algorithm - K-Nearest Neighbour algorithm(Weka API)

WORK EXPERIENCE

1.Oracle Financial Services Software, Bangalore

Application Developer (March 2012 – November 2012)

Worked on Oracle Banking Platform, a core banking product. Worked on a new feature called MapMyDay which is cash prediction for a teller (i.e. Predicting how much amount of cash will be required for a teller in a particular hour on a particular day in order to efficiently service customers and also efficiently use cash). This is done using a Artificial Neural Network algorithm (Weka) based on historical data and the current day's significance of whether it is a pay day or a holiday.

2.Redbus.in, Bangalore

Software Engineer(November 2010 – January 2012)

- Worked on SeatSeller (http://www.seatseller.in), India's first Global Distribution System for Bus industry. Features include Search Routes, Seat Availability Data, Reports on accounting and ticketing.
- Worked on new features and enhancements like reporting various data for the agents for a SaaS application named Bus Operator Software Services (http://boss.travel), which handles all the needs of a bus operator to manage inventory, accounting, reporting and ticketing.
- Worked on a internal product for managing finance and cash collection of the company.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Name: S. Raja Ayyappan Date of Birth: June 11, 1989

Gender: Male Nationality: Indian

Current Company: Oracle Financial Services Software, Bangalore.

CTC: Rs.7, 41,030

ECTC: Nil

Notice Period: Immediate

Permanent Address: 59-A, VOC Street, VGN Nagar, Nolambur,

Chennai-600095, India Mobile No: 8148161310 Languages: English and Tamil

Hobbies: Reading Books and Listening to music.





بيتس بلاني - دبي المدينة الأكاديمية الدولية دبي

To Whosoever It May Concern Recommendation Letter

Raja Ayyappan, a Computer Science student at BITS Pilani-Dubai, has worked with me on his undergraduate thesis in the final semester of his study here in designing and analyzing Cloud Computing Architectures using a prototype.

Raja is an enthusiastic, sincere, and hardworking student. He had quite a few sittings with me in Fall 2010 to discuss the possibility of working with me on his thesis – this is unusual with most students. He is a willing worker and a willing learner. From my 10-11 years of experience in the industry, I see the potential in him to work well in teams. Raja chose to work on Cloud Computing and this is a testimony to his willingness to get into unknown territory. He has the ability to push through to get to the end – I have seen him down only for a weekend when he did not perform to *his* expectations in the midterm seminar and then picked up where he left off to finish the thesis.

In Raja's thesis, he defined a Cloud Computing Architecture and developed a prototype that included the client application, a middle ware, and a gateway and servers on the cloud. The architecture includes an ORB. His core work was to estimate the application computational requirements prior to execution and prior to the client selecting a cloud for its execution.

Raja is technically sound and is a capable programmer. In his thesis he has used programming, database access, Computer Architecture/Crganization, and Neural Networks concepts. He also has good problem solving skills. Raja is able to program in Java and C. He has done a good job on integrating embedded programming into solving the thesis problem.

Dr. Anand Kumar Associate Professor

Contact: akumar@bitsdubai.com

B.E. (Hons) in Electrical and Electronics Engineering, BITS Pilani
MS & PhD in Electrical & Computer Engineering, Rice University, Houston, TX, USA.
Taught previously at New York Institute of Technology, Abu Dhabi, UAE.
8 years at Motorola India (Bangalore) and Ericsson (Bangalore, India and Dallas, TX, USA).

